因此，这使我们得出了我们的结论。
So that brings us to
the conclusion of our course.
你幸存了下来你幸存了下来你在库伯内特幸存下来
You survived Builder, you survived podman,
you survived Kubernetes,
你的简历就像我幸存下来一样
that's something that you can like right
on your resume that like I survived
库伯内特好吗
Kubernetes, all right?
你学到了很多关于 Docker的东西，很棒，你学会了
You learned a lot of stuff about Docker,
which is awesome, you learned
容器是什么你学会了如何手工制作容器
what a Container is, you learned how
to handcraft container which is, again,
很多人每天都能用容器
what more than a lot of people can
do that use containers every day.
您将了解 Docker 是什么，在何处有用，如何为 Docker 设置 Docker 文件
You'll learn what Docker is, where it can
be useful, how to set up Docker files for
开发和生产，如何在 Docker中设置网络，绑定安装，
both development and production, how to
set up networks in Docker, bind mounts,
卷， Docker 编写，然后进行大量介绍
volume, Docker compose and
then a great introduction to
大型生态系统是 Podman 和 Builder 之类的
the Ecosystem at large which would be
Podman and Builder and stuff like that.
我认为这将会立即帮助你成为一名工程师
The things that I think that will
immediately help you as an engineer,
作为开发者是如何开发共享开发者容器，
as a developer is how to make
a share developer container,
我觉得这很有用
I think that's very useful.
如何使用一些我们可以使用或使用的 Visual Studio 代码
How to make that work with Visual Studio
Code which a few of us could use or
这对你来说是很有用的
make that very useful for
you right away, how to get up and
如果有人给你一个容器对吧
going if someone gives
you a container right?
比如你办公室的人指控集装箱
Like if someone from your office
teams has accused the container
你知道该怎么做对吧
now you know what to do with it, right?
然后如何启动更小的规模
And then how to start smaller scale like
多容器项目由 Docker 组成，然后最终由 Kubernetes组成。
multi container projects with Docker
compose and then eventually Kubernetes.
我觉得这些都是关键的，马上有用的 takeawways，
I think those are like the key,
immediately useful takeaways,
我认为其他一切都只是在了解容器周围的生态系统。
I think everything else is just kind of
knowing the ecosystem around containers.
然后我觉得容器会变得越来越重要，对吧 ?
And then I think containers are just gonna
become more and more important, right?
有些像技术我已经证明你越来越多
Some of these like techniques that
I've shown you are becoming more
像微软和谷歌这样的公司
common at companies like Microsoft and
Google and
我想这也会渗透到这些更小的公司，对吧 ?
I think that's going to permeate down into
these smaller companies as well, right?
所以我觉得如果你在这条曲线的过程中
So I think you're ahead of the curve if
you've gotten this far in the course of
那里的生态系统和产业环境的发展
where the ecosystem and where
the environment of the industry is going.
还有其他很酷的事情我们没说过
And there's other things really
cool that we didn't talk about,
Azure 容器的实例 AWS Fargate
things like Azure Container Instances,
AWS Fargate,
Google 云运行， Visual Studio Online 是另一个非常酷的版本。
Google Cloud Run, Visual Studio Online
is another one that's really cool.
这些都是围绕着容器
And these are all things that
are centered around containers
例如 CI Azure 容器实例或 " 法门 " 或 " 云运行" 。
like something like a CI Azure Container
instances or Fargate, or Cloud Run.
你要做的就是让云提供商像我的容器一样
What you do is you give the cloud
providers like here's my container, and
那么云提供者只需要在容器中运行，然后开始运行
then the cloud provider just takes in
the container and starts running it and
它会放大和缩小你的规模这是他们的无服务器的容器
then it'll scale it up and scale down for
you, it's their serverless containers.
你不用管他们你不需要把它们放大
And you don't have to manage them,
you dont have to scale them or
任何类似的事情都是很有效的
anything like that, everything just kind
of works so definitely check those out,
这些都很有趣
those are a lot of fun.
所以我要来这里的笔记我们要过去几个月
So I'm gonna come in here to the notes,
and we're just gonna go over some last
如果你有兴趣的话你可以去做一些生态系统
ecosystem things that you can go and do
more investigation if you're interested.
所以它就在结论部分。
So it's here in the conclusion section.
所以如果你想要更多的集装箱运行时间来建造一个 Podman 和
So if you want more container runtimes
alternatives to build a Podman and
Docker，有 lxc 和 lxd。
Docker, there's lxc and lxd.
所以 lxc ，这也是开的容器， LINUX 基金会的
So lxc, this also comes out of the open
container, LINUX foundation kind
基于 lxc 的 Docker ，因此它是一种基本的构建块。
of project, Docker used to based on lxc so
it's kind of a fundamental building block.
所以它也基于容器， lxd 是守护程序
And so it's also based around containers,
lxd is the daemon that
在后台运行，使用 lxd 与 Docker的概念。
runs in the background,
the idea with lxd versus Docker.
Docker 的构建非常重要我想旋转并销毁容器
Docker is very much build for, I'm wanna
spin up and destroy containers and
我不太在意我经常这样做对吧
I don't really care how
frequently I do that, right?
什么都不是为了永远活下去
Nothing is meant to live forever,
一切都是一次性的那种 Docker 的方式
everything is disposable,
that's kind of the Docker way.
对于将要运行的容器，此值为 lxd
With lxd this is meant for
containers that are gonna be running for
很长时间了对吧
a very long time, right?
这样你就会把容器转掉然后你就进去
So these ones you gonna spin off
a container, then you gonna go in and
你要定制它对吧
you gonna customize it, right?
Lxd 是你想继续跑的雪花容器
Lxd is for snowflake containers that
you wanna keep running for a very,
很长时间了
very long time.
然后有火箭，就是 CoreOS 和 CoreOS 买的
Then there's rocket, rkt which is from
CoreOS and CoreOS just got bought by
Red Hat 和 Red Hat 由 IBM 购买，因此 IBM 最终拥有火箭。
Red Hat and Red Hat got bought by IBM so
IBM eventually owns rocket.
它对 CoreOS 有很大的意义，它的核心是播客。
It's very much meant to pair with CoreOS
and it has the core idea of pods.
这就是和库伯内特一样的想法
And this is the exact same idea of pods
to Kubernetes where you have these
全部捆绑在一起的五个容器的原子部署
atomic deployments of five containers that
are all bundled together, that's built
而 Docker 并不一定会有 " 药 " 的概念，对吧 ?
into rocket whereas Docker doesn't
necessarily have a concept of pods, right?
所以如果你有这个想法，那么火箭是适合你的，
So if you have that idea,
then rocket's a good fit for you,
它也建在 CoreOS里
it's also built into CoreOS,
所以如果你有兴趣的话，在 CoreOS 里，火箭是很适合的。
so if you're interested in that, in
CoreOS, then rockets a good fit for that.
好吧我们讨论了库珀内特是一个编排系统
Okay, and so we talked about Kupernetes
which is an orchestration system,
这就是 Kubernetes 的问题这是一个容器编排系统
that's what you would call Kupernetes,
it's a container orchestration system.
还有几个您可能也想知道的， Docker Swarm so
There are a few others that you might
wanna be aware of as well, Docker Swarm so
内置 Docker。
built into Docker.
事实上如果你来这里关闭这个小镇
In fact, if you come in here
to close this close this town.
如果你说码头这么热的话这里就有一堆东西
If you say docker swarm like that,
there's a whole bunch of stuff in here
如何启动 swarms 和 swarms 与 Kubernetes 差不多，对吧 ?
about how to initiate swarms and swarms
are comparable to Kubernetes, right?
您可以管理多个容器，
You can have multiple
containers being managed,
我喜欢他们是如何使用 Docker Swarm 管理的。
I like how they're managed
with Docker Swarm.
因此，如果您对 Kubernetes 感兴趣，那么我链接到他们的文档
So I link to their to their documentation
if you're interested in doing Kubernetes
就像东西，但是群热，更简单，更简单，
like things, but with swarm,
it's simpler, it's simpler,
它的威力比库伯内特还小
it's less powerful than Kubernetes.
所以我也很想教这个，因为我觉得这样更好
So it's actually very tempted to teach
that too because I think it's a better
但问题是人们想知道库伯内特对吧
way to get started with it but the thing
is people wanna know Kubernetes, right?
每个人都这么说每个人都很感兴趣
That's what everyone's saying,
everyone's very interested and
就像是决定走那条路但如果你有兴趣的话
it's like decided to go that path but
if you're interested in,
我肯定会建议你选 " 码头工人 " 的表格
I would definitely suggest
you pick on Dockers form.
在另一边是 Apache Mesos
On other side of that is Apache Mesos and
Mesos 超级难我甚至都无法开始
Mesos is super hard,
like I can't even get it started and
我甚至不开玩笑我也不知道
I'm not even joking and
try to get it started and I couldn't.
所以它比库伯内特更有力量
So, it's even more powerful
perhaps than Kubernetes,
我不知道我能不能备份它但它和库伯内特一样强大
I don't know if I can back it up but it's
as powerful as Kubernetes at least, but
那是很难用的
it's just very difficult to use.
他们在所谓的 " 中心圈 " 上面建了一层
They've actually built a layer on top of
the called Mesosphere which allows it
就能变得更简单一些
to be a little bit more simple to use on.
现在在美斯圈的上面还有一层
And now there's another layer on top of
Mesosphere and the name escapes me but
它的层在非常难以使用的层上但它也一样
it's layers upon layers of being very
difficult to use, but it does the same
将复杂应用程序与 Mesos 协调的地方。
thing where you can orchestrate
complex applications with Mesos.
Mesos 是从推特上出来的对吧
Mesos came out of Twitter, right?
现在，所有 Twitter 的基础设施都与 Mesos建立了
So now, all of Twitter's
infrastructure is built with Mesos,
就像谷歌发明了 Kubernetes
whereas like Google invented Kubernetes.
所以他们有一个叫做 Borg 的系统
So they have a system called Borg and
they kind of export that architecture and
变成了库伯内特
that became Kubernetes.
在谷歌内部，他们仍然使用 Borg，
Internally inside of Google,
they still use Borg,
不过以防你在想
though, just in case you're wondering.
我想梅索斯是在伯克利发明的
So I guess Mesos was
invented at Berkeley and
然后推特通过了我认为这是更准确的方法
then Twitter adopted it I think that's
more accurate way of putting it.
现场的新人是哈希科普流浪者，我提到你们很多人知道，
The newcomer on the scene is a Hashicorp
Nomad, I mentioned many of you know,
Hasicorp，他们做了 Vagrant，他们做了 Terraform ，他们做了控制台。
Hashicorp, they did Vagrant,
they did Terraform, they did console.
他们做了很多 DevOps 工程师非常喜欢的工具
They do a lot of tools that DevOps
engineers really quite like,
我自己也包括，我认为哈希科普是一家伟大的公司，做的很棒。
myself included, I think Hashicorp is
a great company doing great stuff.
所以他们最近和流浪者和流浪者
And so they have recently come
out with Nomad and Nomad is
Kubernetes 对你做了很多事
much more limited than Kubernetes,
Kubernetes does a lot of stuff for you,
比如负载平衡和其他的东西对吧
like load balancing and
a whole bunch of other stuff, right?
它把盒子里的一切都做了
It does everything out of the box,
it's meant to be the kitchen sink of
编排工具， Nomad 只是编排部分，不是其他内容。
orchestration tools, Nomad is just the
orchestration part and it is nothing else.
那么，如果你进入这个，就像这个 Unix 的方法，
So, if you're into that, kind of,
that Unix methodology of, like,
这个工具做一件事它做得非常好
this tool does one thing, and
it does it super well, and
没别的事了诺马很可能是你要找的
it is literally nothing else, Normad
is probably what you're looking for.
所以它的意思是要用 Terraform 之类的东西来配对
So, it's meant to pair with things,
like, Terraform, and
控制台和保险库文件及其各种不同的工具。
Console, and Vault and all their
various different tools together.
比如说，我们不把库伯内特作为一个秘密的管理，对吗 ?
Like, for example, we didn't talk about
Kubernetes as a secret management, right?
这里有一个秘密管理工具
There's a secret management
tool built into Kubernetes,
它不是被提名为 Nomad他们有一个单独的产品名叫 Hasicorp Vault
it's not built into Nomad, they have
a separate product called Hashicorp Vault,
这就是把它和流浪者配对的意思
and that's meant to pair
it together with Nomad.
所以，看看这个，人们都喜欢这样
So, check that as well,
people are liking it so
我只能这么说但我喜欢和相信哈希科普
that's all I really can say about that but
I like and trust Hashicorp.
我们没有真正谈论的事情是什么是主人
Something that we didn't really talk
a ton about is what is the host,
您的服务器在生产中的运行情况，对吗 ?
what is running your servers
in production, right?
有时你只是把你的容器给 Azure 然后说，嘿， Azure，
Now sometimes you're just giving your
containers to Azure and say, hey, Azure,
给我执行这个吧
execute this for me, right?
在这种情况下你不关心的是什么
In which case you don't care
about what's running it because
云供应商正在选择它而不选择您。
the cloud provider is choosing it and
not you.
但如果你正在运行自己的 VM 并且 VM正在执行您的容器，
But if you're running your own VM's and
your VM's are executing your containers,
你得选择主机操作系统是什么
you'd have to choose what
the host operating system is.
所以，有一个叫做 CoreOS 容器 Linux。
So, there's one called
CoreOS Container Linux.
这是或者有人称它为 CoreOS
This is, or people just call it CoreOS,
他们不区分 Linux 的不同但
they don't separate out
the Container Linux is different but
它实际上被称为 " 容器 Linux " ，由 CoreOS制作。
it actually technically is called
Container Linux and is made by CoreOS.
它是一个最小的 Linux 操作系统主机，是最受欢迎的
So it's a minimal Linux OS host,
it's one of the most popular ones for
而且它刚装了一堆工具让它很简单
sure and it just shipped with a bunch
of tools that make it very simple
来开始使用容器所以这是非常受欢迎的
to get started with containers so
that's a very popular one.
我喜欢 RancherOS，那天开始玩，
I like RancherOS,
I started playing with the other day and
只是一个很奇怪的操作系统很有趣
it's just a It's a very strange
operating system in a fun way, that
通常你就像像 PID1 一样的巴什一样，就像第一个执行的事情，
normally you have like bashes like the
PID1, like the first thing that execute,
Ranchero 都是由 Docker 来执行的，一切都是一个容器。
with Ranchero is everything is executed
by Docker, everything is a container.
因此，如果在 Rancher 中执行任何操作，那么将执行以下操作 :
So if you execute anything within Rancher,
it's Docker that's doing the execution of
所以每个过程都是一个容器，真的很有趣。
it so every single process is a container,
which is really, really fun.
所以，一定要给它一次机会。
So, definitely give it a shot.
有一个叫 Ubuntu，我想我们都听说过，对吧 ?
There's one called Ubuntu,
I think we've all heard of this, right?
Ubuntu 是很好的执行容器，我觉得他们有一个项目
Ubuntu is really great executing
containers, I think they have a project
它的意思是，它们就像它的一个特定的分布。
that actually is meant, they have
like a specific distribution of it.
我记不起这叫 " 蛇"
I can't remember it's called a Snappy,
可能被称为 " 蛇 " 之类的但你也可以用 Fedora
might be called Snappy something like
that but you can also use Fedora,
您可以使用 DBN，其中任何一个 Linux 操作系统。
you can use DBN,
any one of those Linux Operating Systems.
没有为容器构建，但构建为
There are not built for
containers, but they are built for
一切都是如此但容器是一切的一部分
everything, but
containers are part of everything so
也可以考虑用这些来思考
it's a valid choice to think
about using those as well.
这里有一个我想叫 DC/OS
And this one out here that
I wanted to called DC/OS,
这与库伯内特和梅索斯的关系非常密切
this is strongly associated not
with Kubernetes with Mesos.
不过，我听说 DC/OS 也绝对可以运行 Kubernetes 。
However, I am told that DC/OS can
definitely run Kubernetes as well and
它可以被控制，你可以让 Mesos 和 Kubernetes 彼此交谈，
it can be controlled, You can have Mesos
and Kubernetes talk to each other,
听起来像是某种地狱我不想待在这里
which just sounds like some sort
of hell that I don't wanna be in.
总之， DC/OS ，它代表
So anyway, DC/OS, which stands for
分布式云操作系统，它非常独特。
Distributed Cloud Operating System,
it's very unique.
是的，人们真的喜欢 DC/OS ，比 Mesos 更喜欢，我从没用过
Yeah, people really like DC/OS more than
they like Mesos, I've never used it so
我不会再跟你说这事了但人们喜欢
I'm not gonna tell you anything more
about it than that, but people like it.
然后 VMWare Photon 来自公司 VMWare
And then VMWare Photon comes
from the company VMWare
这使得一些你可能已经在使用的工具
which makes a bunch of tools that
you probably are already using.
他们最近提出了自己的集装箱 IOS 操作系统
They recently came up with their own
container IOS operating system called
Photon 的意思是对他们的其他工具比如 vSphere 之类的
Photon so it's meant to mostly pair into
their other tools like vSphere and such.
所以我觉得我们有观众的一些好的问题，
So I think we had some good
questions from the audience,
其中一个我记得的是网上的人群，其中一个被问到的是，
one of them I remember that are from the
online crowd, one of the they asked was,
CMD 和 Rin 之间有什么区别 ?
what's the difference between CMD and Rin?
所以，让我们来看看这个问题。
So let's go take a look
at that really quick.
这是我的 Docker 文件你可以看到我有 RUN
Here my Docker file,
you can see here I have RUN,
最后我在这里有 CMD
and I have CMD down here at the end.
其中一个是在运行时完成的，其中一个是在构建时完成的。
One of these is done at runtime and
one of them is done at build time so
RUN，这将会在我说 Docker 构建后立即运行，对吗 ?
RUN, this is going to get run as
soon as I say Docker built, right?
所以当你在建筑的时候要做所有的依赖性
So you're gonna do all the dependencies
installing when you're building
容器和 CMD 就是你告诉 Docker 的地方
the container and CMD is where you're
telling Docker is like when someone
运行此容器，当有人运行 Docker 时，运行此操作，对吗 ?
runs this container, when someone
does Docker run, Run this, right?
这是在运行时，这是构建时间。
So this is at runtime,
this is a build time.
您也很可能有多个 Docker Run 或
You are also very likely gonna
have multiple Docker Run or
你可以在这里看到我在这里有三个 RUNs
you gonna have RUN and you can see
here I have three RUNs in here.
而你最多只拥有一个 CMD
Whereas you only ever
have at most one CMD.
>> 也可以和盖茨比建立起来
&gt;&gt; Can this be set up with Gatsby as well,
那些有 VS 码延期的人帮我安排好了吗
and those having a VS Code extension
help set this up pretty easy?
这是问题。
This is the question.
>> 当然，就像我们以前雨果一样，你能和盖茨比一起做吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Sure, like we did Hugo before,
could you do this with Gatsby?
答案是绝对的，对吧 ?
And the answer is absolutely, right?
所以如果你像盖茨比项目那样
So if you had like a Gatsby project and
你和一群不知道如何使用 Node 和 NPM 的人合作
you're working with a bunch of people that
didn't know how to use Node and NPM and
所有这些东西你都可以把它装在一个容器里
all that kind of stuff, you could
totally wrap this up in a container.
它也能起作用我的猜测可能是
It would work just as well,
my guess is that there's probably,
已由 Gatsby 容器或 Docker 执行完全相同的操作。
already a Gatsby container or
Docker does the exact same thing.
所以，当然，你绝对可以做到这一点。
So yeah, for sure,
you can definitely do that.
我不太喜欢这里的东西，卡兹提到的 VS .
Something I didn't really get into as much
in here, cuz the person mentioned VS Code
是 VS 代码的 Docker 扩展。
is the Docker extension for VS Code.
你可以在这里看到我的所有容器
You can see here that it shows
me all of my containers or
事实上我可以在这里看到我的建造商集装箱实际上还在运行，
in fact, I can see here that my builder
container is actually still running,
我只能说你知道吗我不干了
and I can just say, you know what,
I'm done with this, stop and
就像这样把我的容器停下来
it will just stop my container for
me, just like that.
在这里我可以跑来跑，我可以拉集装箱，我的所有照片都是
And here I can come here and run, I can
pull containers, here's all my images that
我拉了我能看到的各种高山，我有各种
I've pulled where I can see that I have
various versions of alpine, I have various
节点应用程序的版本，构建器， codesmith ，这是我刚才构建的
versions of node app, builder, codesmith
that's one that I built awhile ago for
我们的好朋友会被判刑的
our good friend, will sentence, actually.
所以这也是值得查的
So, this is something worth
checking out as well so
你可以看到我也和 Azure 登记处有联系，那是真的吗 ?
you can see I'm also connected to
an Azure registry, is that true?
否，我要登录，但您可以将其连接到 Azure ，您可以将其连接到
No, I would have to sign in but you can
connect it to Azure, you can connect it to
谷歌或者 GitHub ，或者所有这些东西。
Google, or GitHub, or
all these things as well, yeah.
>> 另一个问题，
&gt;&gt; Another question,
究竟怎样才是最有效的方法来监察货柜上的警报呢 ?
what would be the best way to monitor an
alert on containers going down at scale?
>> 这是一个好问题，最好的监控方法是什么 ?
&gt;&gt; That is a good question,
what's the best way to monitor?
有很多产品是给你做的，你可以用的东西
There's a lot of products that do this for
you, you can go as far as using things
就像新遗迹一样运作良好，对容器有特殊的东西。
like New Relic which work really well and
they have specific things for containers.
每个云提供者都有不同的监控机制，
Each of the cloud provider has various
different mechanisms for monitoring,
就像 Azure 我们有 App Insights ，我认为它是 AWS 的云观察。
like Azure we have App Insights,
I think it's Cloud Watch for AWS.
我不记得 GCP 的叫什么但都有自己的具体
I don't remember what GCP's is called,
but they all have their own specific
这些咒语的咒语
incantations thereof That being said,
可能还有其他工具可以使用 StatsD 和 NSCD之类的东西。
there are probably other tools like you
can use things like StatsD and NSCD.
不是 NSCD 而是 StatsD 做某种综合记录
Not NSCD but rather StatsD for
doing some sort of consolidated logging,
那里有很多不同的产品
there's a lot of different
products out there.
我对他们中的任何一个都不熟悉
I'm not more familiar with any
one of them than the other,
还有 Sentry ， Sentry 是个好的。
there's also Sentry,
Sentry would be a good one.
所以老实说你所关心的
So, honestly there's not much difference
between what you would be concerned about
与 Kubernetes 的工作相比，正常的 Web Service 正在做什么。
versus what Kubernetes is doing,
versus what a normal web service is doing.
你会用同样的方式对待大部分的人
You're gonna treat them relatively
the same way for the most part.
有些特殊的 Kubernetes 的东西
There's some specific Kubernetes stuff,
and
您的云供应商将为您提供该服务。
your cloud provider will provide that for
you.
好吧恭喜你
All right, well, congratulations.
这是一个非常技术性的话题，
This is a deeply technical topic and
希望你能像你学到的那样
hopefully was presented to you in such
that like you learned something about it,
我为你创造了这个课程很有趣
I had a lot of fun creating
this course for you.
如果你再喜欢它一个开始 GitHub 说很多帮助我
If you liked it again, a start and
GitHub says a lot helps me,
我可以自由地告诉我文件问题和开放的隐私
feel free to Tweeted me,
file issues, open PRs.
我昨晚已经看到有人开公关了所以我要把它合并
I already saw someone open a PR last
night so I'm gonna go merge that so
谢谢你帮我尽最大的努力
thank you for
helping me make the best course possible.
再次感谢 Fronend Masters 和全体船员
Thanks again to Frontend Masters and
the whole crew.
你们都是最好的
You all are the best.
但最终我认为集装箱对你们来说都是重要的工具
But in the end, I think containers are
gonna be important tools for all of you,
是否写 CSS， Haskell 或 NodeJS。
whether you write CSS, Haskell, or NodeJS.
这对每个人都有用而且我想向前看
Like it's useful to everyone,
and I think going forward,
你会领先这条曲线的因为你走了这门课
you are gonna be ahead of that
curve because you took this course.
所以谢谢你
So thank you.
>> [APPLAUSE]
&gt;&gt; [APPLAUSE]